<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<RDoC>
<TEXT><![CDATA[


1|

Subject: Patient Initial Visit Note -Identifying information Date of Service: 

10/15/90Age: 

67Referral Source: 

Dr. Forbes, Quincy DuboisChief Complaint / HPI Chief Complaint (Patients own words) 

We are a family of musicians. It was so fast.History of Present Illness and Precipitating Events 

67 yo recently widowed gentleman with stage IIIA melanoma of back (1/16+nodes), s/p high dose interferon induction (week 5 held 9/2090), whose wife died of an aggressive cancer  months prior to his diagnosis.  Mr. Amaya discussed the process of going from working together with his wife to diagnosis, hospitalization and last 2 days in Hospice. He has valued group counseling through Porter Clinicand continues to be connected to a small group of spouses. Son noticed suspicious mole on his back when staying at home after his wife's service and discussed feelings related to that process. Mr. Amaya shared a sense of seeking meaning, making connections between different friends colleagues getting sick/dying, and a sense of "grasping at anything."  Mr. Amaya has had crhonic difficulty with sleep and  had been on Ativan 1mg nightly- increased by his PCP to 2mg nightly following his wife's death. Since increasing the lorazepam, he is sleeping relatively well.  Difficult sometimes to separate what cancer was for his wife: fast, progressive, leading to death, from his own experience.  Has had strong supports including melanoma team- who expressed their worry about his vulnerability given in context of acute grief and anticipating starting maintenance IFN.  


Currently, sleeping relatively well with Ativan 2mg nightly. does not take more than this dose.  Thoughts race, intermittently overwhelmed and tearful. Able to spend time at low-stress jobs (golf course, anticipating at ski mountain) .  He feels connected to his children and expresses clear future orientation and no desire, intent, or plan to end his life. No access to firearms, no mania, and no psychosis.  Near-episodes of panic.  Important to continue to work- surrounded by supportive people, Rabbi, low-stress job.  and that he remains connected to family. During induction period, significant fatigue and malaise. Also coping with uncertainty in decision-making and lack of control and not able to use previously-effective coping strategies in the same way. He has felt overwhelmed, been frequently tearful, and also been very fatigued.  Also recently with worsening myalgias (in addition to fatigue) and elevated CK identified and patient stopped fibrate a few days prior in consultation with oncology- still significant malaise, weekness.  Thought some ambivalence, future-oriented without suicidal ideation. Thyroid function ok. Difficult to cope w/malaise, but also trying to help him to move on as desired.  Currently anticipating maintenance interferon and thinking together about how to maximize tolerability. Feels best when engaged in los-stress post-retirement jobs (ie at retail stores). Open to taking medication for depression or anxiety, particularly if it can help sleep/worry.   Asking good/understandable questions comparing  aschool "No current alcohol or drugs other than nicotine.Suicidal Behavior Hx of Suicidal Behavior: No
Hx of Non Suicidal Self Injurious Behavior: No
Violent Behavior Hx of Violent Behavior: No
-Psychiatric History Hx of Inpatient Treatment: No
Hx of Outpatient Treatment: 

on Ativan nightly for >2 yrs for sleepOther Agency Involvement: No
Psychiatric Review of Systems DEPRESSION: Has the patient had periods of time lasting two weeks or longer in which, most of the day on most days, they felt little interest or pleasure in doing things, or they had to push themselves to do things: Yes
DEPRESSION: Has the patient had periods of time lasting two weeks or longer in which, most of the day on most days, they felt sad, down, or depressed: Yes
BIPOLAR: Has patient ever had a period of time when he/she felt "up" or "high" without the use of substances: No
BIPOLAR: Has patient ever had periods of being persistently irritable for several days, or had verbal/physical fights that seemed clearly out of character: No
PSYCHOSIS: Has the patient had unusual experiences that are hard to explain: No
PSYCHOSIS: Does the patient often have thoughts that make sense to them, but that other people say are strange: No
GAD: Has the patient had times when they worried excessively about day to day matters for most of the day, more days than not: Yes
PANIC: Has the patient had episodes of sudden intense anxiety with physical sensations such as heart palpitations, trouble breathing, or dizziness that reached a peak very quickly and presented without warning: Yes
Alcohol Use: How often did you have a drink containing alcohol in the past year: Two to four times a month (2 points)
How many drinks containing alcohol did you have on a typical day when you were drinking in the past year: 1 or 2 (0 points)
How often did you have six or more drinks on one occasion in the past year: Never (0 points)
Longitudinal Alcohol use History: 

2Drug Use: History of drug use: No
Marijuana: No
Caffeine / Tobacco Use Smoker Status: Former smoker
Packs per day: 1
If patient is a former smoker, last date the patient smoked: 

30 years ago (2060)Family Psych History: Family History of Suicidal Behavior: None
Family History of Violent Behavior: None
Family History of Substance Abuse: No
-Medical History Date of Last Phys. Exam / PCP Appoint.: 

10/06/90Hx of Brain Injury: No
Medical History: 

1. Stage IIIA melanoma of Right side of back, dx: June 2090, s/p high dose INF-alpha induction (some doses held)

2. Hypertesion

- GERD, varicose veins

 Prior relevant labs: 

TSH wnl, see HPI re: elevated CK, symptomatic and potential treatment strategies. Pertinent Medical Review of Systems Constitutional: 

fatigue, weaknessMusculoskeletal (back/extremities): 

myalgiasActivities of Daily Living (ADL) Bathing: Independent
Dressing: Independent
Grooming: Independent
Oral Care: Independent
Toileting: Independent
Transferring: Independent
Walking: Independent
Climbing Stairs: Independent
Eating: Independent
Problems Malignant melanoma 
Hypertensive disorder 
Allergies NKA 
Medications Compazine (PROCHLORPERAZINE Maleate) 10 MG (10MG TABLET Take 1) PO Q6H PRN nausea; No Change 
Diltiazem 180 MG (Take 1) PO TID; No Change , Comments: 180mg PO qD
Folic Acid 1 MG (1 MG TABLET Take 1) PO AC; No Change , Comments: 1mg PO in AM
Intron A (INTERFERON-ALFA-2B) 50MM UNIT VIAL Take 0.48 mL SC 3x/week, Dose: 24 million units subq thrice weekly X 48 weeks. Dosing:(10 million units/m2) HT 76 in, WT 236 lbs. BSA = 2.4. Dose will be 0.48 mL Subq 3 x per week Do not substitute vial size, patient educated on this dose. ; No Change 
Lisinopril 10 MG (10 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD; No Change 
Lorazepam 2 MG (1 MG TABLET Take 2) PO QHS PRN anxiety/insomnia; No Change 
Omeprazole 20 MG (20 MG TABLET DR Take 1) PO BID; No Change 
Physical Therapy Take 1 PO 3x/week x 31 days; No Change , Comments: Physical therapy to right arm 3/week.
Sertraline 50 MG (50 MG TABLET Take 1) PO QD, Take 1/2 tablet daily for 1 week, then increase to 1 tablet daily. ; New 
Pain Treatment Pain: No
Pain Level (Numeric Scale): 5
Referral/Treatment Needed: No
Social History Does patient have any children: Yes

adult children close by, supports Interpersonal Interactions/ Concerns: 

strong family network of support and close friends, and established support from hospiceHistory of Significant Losses: 

wife's death from aggressive cancer in March 2090Spiritual/Religion: 

JewishMeaningful activities/supports: 

skiing, golf, moviesEducation Education Level: College Grad
Learning Disabilities: No
Employment Currently employed: Yes
Occupation/Work History: 

had been musician for career "a family of musicians", retired early with goal of traveling, spending time with his wife, and able to do that together. Now clerk at golf course, or similar in CO at ski mountain.Financial Stress: No
Living Situation Current Living Situation (Including type of dwelling and who patient lives with): 

lives alone (recently widowed), manages his own medications, multiple supports close byFirearms: None
Does patient feel safe in current living situation: Yes
Is Patient at risk of losing current housing: No
In-Home Services: None
Legal History NoMilitary Service History: Hx of Military Service: Uncertain
-Mental Status Exam Was the exam performed? (If not, indicate reason): Yes
Appearance: WNL
Clothing: WNL
Facial Expression: Intermittently tearful; Anxious/Fearful
Eye Contact: WNL
Build: WNL

has had some wt lossPosture: WNL
Speech: WNL
Body Movement: Slowed; Restless

notes recent acute worsening of fatigue/myalgias in context of high CK, oncology team aware and followingBehavior: Cooperative
Attention: Adequate
Orientation: WNL
Emotional State-Mood: Sad
Emotional State-Affect: Congruent to mood
Neurovegetative Symptoms: sleep; interest; energy; appetite
Thought Process: WNL
Perception: WNL
Hallucinations: None
Delusions: None Reported
Other Thought Content: Preoccupied
Self Abuse Thoughts: None Reported
Suicidal Thoughts: None Reported
Aggressive Thoughts: None Reported
Risk Assessment Did patient endorse thoughts of harm to self or others during today's session: No
Protective Factors: 

relationship w/adult children, engaged in treatmentModifiable risk factors: 

anxiety, depressionPatient's current risk status: Appropriate for continued outpatient treatment
Actions taken: Medication changes; Continue to monitor, patient (or family/guardian) agrees to call or go to emergency room if symptoms worsen
Does patient have chronic high risk: No
Multi-Axial Diagnoses/Assessment Axis I (code and description): 

Acute grief reaction

309.28 adjustment disorder with anxiety and depressed moodEating Disorders 307.5 Eating Disorder, NOS
Axis II (Personality Disorders): DEFERRED
Axis III: 

Stage IIIA melanoma, IFNAxis IV: Other psych/social/environmental problems; Problems related to social environment

loss of spouseAxis V- (GAF) Current: 55
Impression Strengths/Abilities: 

strong family support, resilient, pragmaticFormulation: 

67 yo gentleman with Stage IIIA melanoma and no formal psychiatric history, recently widowed after wife rapidly died following cancer diagnosis.  Difficulty tolerating interferon and now coping w/physical symptoms related to elevated CK. Encouragingly, h/o effective coping- able to mobilize a group of widows that he sees every month or so. Given constellation of current symptoms: tearfulness, poor sleep, high worry: recommend starting SSRI to provide protection against developing a major depressive episode. Will also be important to follow=up with oncology team (and PCP)  to ensure CK heading in right direction after stopping fibrate. In addition to medication, discussed behavioral strategies- remaining active around supportive community will be critical.  Not at imminent risk of harm to self and outpt care appropriate. Over time, may also be able to taper back to baseline dose of lorazepam.  Will benefit from regular monitoring of mood and anxiety and engagement with family. Patient Instructions 

1. Start sertraline 25mg daily and Substance Use Intervention Action Plan: None needed; Continue to monitor
Patient Response: Accepted
-Recommendations / Plan Level of Care: Outpatient

1. Start SSRI targeting anxiety and prevention of mood changes on maintenance interferon, work on slow taper of lorazepam from 2mg-1.5mg after sertraline therapeutic

2. Consder mirtazapine as additional option for sleep/anxiety/mood

3. Referred to NMF, support with continued connection with hospice caregivers' group and staying active as possibleIf outpatient treatment recommended please specify modality: Nuuanu Medical Facility (NMF); Medication Treatment
Prescriptions Given: 

sertralineMedication and treatment risks and benefits discussed? Yes
Labs/Other Studies Ordered: 

none- tsh okIs the patient being referred for further medical or neurological assessments (Please specify): No
Patient response to/preferences regarding treatment recommendations: Accepts
This visit for a one-time consultation only? No
Date of Return Visit: 

2-3 wksCommunication with referring physician?: Done
 [report_end]


]]></TEXT>
</RDoC>